Translation and subtitles by PEPPER LALASPAIN * * * SONG LIVES FOR EVER * * *
Strange .
Who 'd do something like this ?
Maybe someone got a little upset about their roaming charges .
Stealing satellite phones makes sense . You can hock them .
You can run up charges on somebody else 's account .
But burning them ?
Youngsters ?
Pulling some prank ?
No .
They 'd have left a note .
" Fuck you " to their parents ...
or the world or whatever .
Not a bad idea , though .
I brought Peggy here on our first date .
Yeah , we all did .
Not Peggy , of course .
Yeah , I got you .
Last sunset in a month ...
Always works .
Come on . Let 's go do the sign .
You okay , Eben ?
Yeah .
Why do you even bother with that ? Nobody 's gonna see it for a month .
It 's tradition .
You kind of put this off till the last minute , didn 't you ?
There 's a lot of small towns in this state .
My boss wants all his gear inspected and certified by the 31st .
And I noticed you saved Barrow for the last .
You sure you don 't wanna stay ?
Me and Jeannie were hoping you and Eben might rethink this separation thing .
Thanks .
I ...
Gotta make the plane .
Okay , sweetie . I know you can 't handle a month with no sun .
I promise I won 't live on Oreos and Snapple , all right ?
Have fun in Seattle .
Yeah . So long , Kirsten .
I 'll call you when I get there .
Goodbye .
Got a problem ?
Nothing I can 't handle my own fucking self .
This for generators ?
Yeah . Yeah , mostly .
Beau , I 'm gonna have to cite you for it .
I can 't have it leaking all over the street the street .
What ?
You ... ?
For that ? You don 't ...
You don 't have to cite me .
You don 't have to do anything .
Isn 't that why we live out here ?
You know , for a little freedom ?
Happy motoring .
Yeah , I 'll add it to my collection .
You know , Beau 's not so bad . Why 'd you bother writing him up ?
He lives all alone out there on the south ridge .
A little citation now and then lets him know he 's a part of this town .
Eben ? Come in , Eben .
Yeah , Helen .
Something bad 's happened to John Riis ' dogs .
Well , folks , you 're listening to KBRW , Barrow , Alaska .
Today 's the last day ...
I 'm leaving too , getting on that last plane out of here .
Hey , Stella , are you okay ?
Damn it , Malekai .
Don 't you know what " right of way " means ?
I 'm sorry , Stella .
The brakes jammed and ...
Eben wanted this back from the airport before the storm hit , and I was ...
Oh , shit . Who 's gonna run me to the airport ?
Well , wouldn 't Eben ?
My mom could come down and give you a tow ,
but you know she don 't move too fast .
Fuck ! Where 's my phone ?
It 's me .
Surprise .
I need a ride to the airport .
What ?
You 're in town , and you didn 't wanna talk ?
I had fire-Marshal work here , and I just had a little accident , and ...
I 'm stuck on Ransom and 355 ,
and he airport will close and I 'll never get to Anchorage .
I mean , if you wanna talk , we can do it on the drive .
Hey , Billy !
Stella 's stuck at Ransom and 355 .
She needs a ride to the airport . Can you go get her ?
Yeah .
Stella , John Riis needs me for something ,
so Billy 's gonna come get you .
Let me know if a day comes when you do wanna talk .
What sick jerk would do this ?
Every kennel . Every dog we had .
Did you fight with anyone recently , John ?
I 'll kill them .
This wasn 't done long ago .
I 'll find them . Okay ?
You 'll be okay , Malekai .
- Where have you been ? - I couldn 't find the damn car keys .
Then I was like , " Wait , was that Rogers and 355 or Ransom ? "
- And then ... - Yeah , never mind . Let 's go .
It would be a lot easier if you just played , Grandma .
Oh , I don 't really care for those sort of games , if you wanna know the truth .
Try your brother .
- What ? - Eben , do you wanna play ?
I can 't right now , Jake . Sorry .
While you were busy with John Riis , Carter and Wilson called ...
about a vandalism problem at the Utilidor .
Thanks .
Call Point Hope and Wainwright . See if they 're having any troubles .
No !
I am not trapped here for a month .
There 'll be someone you can bunk with .
Don 't start , Billy .
Peggy and me can put two girls in one room . You 'd have a place of your own .
I can 't stay here . I 've got bills to put in the mail ,
my plants will die .
It 'll all work out .
Of course , the price of staying at my place ,
is explaining to me and Peggy just what is wrong with you and Eben .
Not enough time this century to cover that , Billy .
- Eben , how you doing ? Good to see you . - Hey , Carter .
Lord , it 's gotta be 10 below out here .
- Eben . - Wilson .
Can 't your wife bring you up a sweater or two ?
Bring the whole tribe up while she 's at it ?
They 'll come when they 're ready , I guess .
So ...
I 've found all kinds of garbage in here over the years .
Blue jeans , bikes ...
Sometimes I can yank them out before the muffin monster chews them to shit .
The muffin monster ?
I saw Wilson 's helicopter logo .
Pulled that stuff out before it got totally trashed .
You keep your copter under lock and key , don 't you , Wilson ?
Yeah , I put it in dry dock when the tourists headed south .
I haven 't looked at it for days .
They ripped out the throttle , the rotors , half the fucking helicopter !
It 's my life , Eben .
Why would someone rip the hell out of my bird ?
Hey ! Stop !
Stop ! Stop !
Who are you people ?
No whiskey ?
No rum ?
Alcohol 's illegal this month .
Folks have a hard enough time in the dark without booze making it worse .
Well , forget about the liquor ...
Lucy .
Just bring me a bowl of ...
raw hamburger .
You can only get meat two ways around here , frozen or burnt .
You don 't bring me what I wanna eat , what I wanna drink .
That 's enough , pal .
Leave the lady be .
Hey , what do you say the two of us go outside and have a little talk , huh ?
Well , now , what 's wrong with a man wanting a little fresh meat ?
Come on . You and me , let 's go .
I 'm taking you outside .
I would like to see that .
I would too .
But then Lucy 'd have to clean up after Eben kicked your ass .
It 's more trouble than you 're worth .
Hey , be nice !
Enough .
Stay down .
Fire Marshal 's office lets you carry one of those things ?
It 's a funny thing , I never asked .
So , you missed your flight ?
That sucks . Where you gonna stay ?
Billy and Peggy are putting me up .
Well , I 'll talk to you sometime , I guess .
Hey , listen .
Look , maybe I 'll come along and say hi to Jake and Helen .
Bye , Luce .
We haven 't seen vandalism like this in a long time .
Don 't you know how to take care of this town without me ?
Malekai totaled my car .
Hell of a day .
Just you wait .
Hey , Jake .
- Where are we going ? - I 'm heading back to your house .
My landlady doesn 't want a bunch of pipeline workers keeping her up all night .
Denise is right .
Let 's head back to my place .
Neither of you are getting me alone .
Neither !
We share , right ?
None of us have to be greedy .
- Yeah , come on . We 'll be good . - Oh , you will ?
- Where 's the fun in that , Gabe ? - You bad little bitch .
All right , all right , Rock , Paper , Scissors .
- Whoever wins , we go to his place . - Good idea . Let 's do it .
- Come on . - Hurry up , let 's get moving .
On three .
One , two ...
Gabe ?
Gabe !
Let me tell you what I got .
You don 't work at the refinery .
You didn 't fly in . Somebody 'd have seen you .
And you 're definitely not from around here .
How 'd you get in ?
All right .
We got a long time to figure this out . Nobody 's coming for you for a month .
Jake , come here a second .
What the hell is that ?
It 's pot .
It helps her with her cancer .
Didn 't tell you I got a little greenhouse at home . Didn 't want you arresting me .
Now I know why you wanted to live with Grandma .
No , I just thought you and Stella ought to have some privacy .
Well , that worked out .
Computer 's down .
I 'll call Gus .
Strange .
The phone 's down too .
Mr. and Mrs. Sheriff .
So sweet .
So ...
helpless against what is coming .
He 's just trying to freak us out .
It 's working .
We have more important things to think about .
- I 'll check on Gus . - Check on Gus .
Bar the windows .
Try to hide .
They 're coming .
This time they gonna take me with them ,
honor me .
Yeah . For all that I have done .
" They ? "
Who are " they ? "
The generator 's kicked in .
Translation and subtitles by PEPPER LALASPAIN * * * SONG LIVES FOR EVER * * *
- I 'm heading out to the cell tower . - We have to stay here with him ?
Sure . We 'll keep an eye on him .
As soon as the lines are back up , get Billy over here .
Stay on the walkie-talkie with me until the power 's back .
Gus !
Gus ?
This is Sheriff Eben Oleson .
Stay in your homes , lock your doors ,
and load your firearms . This is not a drill .
Frank , Michelle , is your genny up and running ?
Yeah .
Anyone with a genny should go home immediately , just to be safe .
If you don 't have one , you should meet at the diner .
I heard gunshots , Eben . What the hell is going on ?
I don 't know .
Just go home . I 'll let you know when I find out , okay ?
Okay .
Come on , guys . Let 's go .
Let 's just have dinner , John .
Please ?
John ! John !
- Ally ! - John !
No ! No ! John !
John !
No !
Ally ! Ally !
- John ! John ! - Ally !
- Oh , my God ! - Ally !
Oh , my God . No !
No way out of town .
No one to come help .
- Shut up . - Ignore him , Jake .
You can feel it .
That cold ain 't the weather ,
that 's death approaching .
Who you think they 're gonna take first ? Hmm ?
The girl who thinks a gun will help her ?
The kid , sheriff 's kid ? Or the old gal ?
Shut up !
Oh !
Yeah .
Thank you for the plastique .
I can snap that apart and pick the lock .
No , you won 't .
- Jake , he can 't . Jake . - Jake !
Jake !
You shithead .
Helen , get the first-aid kit .
All right , time to talk . Who are you here with ?
Who are you here with ?
Who did that to Gus ?
You 're a dead man .
Where are they ?
I don 't talk to dead men .
I don 't talk to dead men !
Well , if I 'm dead , no one lets you loose from here .
You 're all dead !
I can take care of that for now , but Doc Miller should ...
No . Wait till the power 's back . Call Doc Miller then .
This fucker doesn 't deserve anything till then .
Billy and I 'll work our way from South Street to the pipeline .
His friends don 't have many places to hide .
I 'll join you .
No , we got it .
Right now , you , me and Billy are the authorities .
It 'd be stupid not to take more help .
We got walkie-talkies . We 'll be fine .
There 's a Taser in the back . If he gives you any trouble ...
use it . Okay ?
You drive . I 'm riding shotgun .
Stop the truck .
What ?
Stop the fucking truck .
I thought I saw something .
- Get in the truck . - What ?
Get in the fucking truck !
- Jesus Christ ! - Fuck !
- Holy shit ! - Fuck !
What the hell was that ?
Shit ! What was that ? Where was that ? Where was that ?
No !
- Helen ! - Help !
Helen ! Helen , come in !
Jake ?
Helen ?
Are you here ?
Oh , shit .
They didn 't take me .
Who did they take ?
Did they take my brother ?
Finish me off .
Finish me .
Eben .
Eben , look at me .
No .
The heads must be separated from the bodies .
Do not turn them .
We should have come here ages ago .
What are they ?
We don 't know .
- Wilson , I wanna go home . - It 's okay . Dad !
It 's okay .
You keep shooting and they just ...
They just keep coming .
- How is that possible ? - I don 't know .
Maybe they 're all coked up on PCP or something , you know .
They don 't feel any bullets .
They killed every sled dog in town .
They took Aaron and Gabe .
They killed my grandmother .
There is no escape .
No hope .
Only hunger and pain .
No !
What are you ? What are you ?
- Lucy , is the back door locked ? - All locked . - Okay .
Jake ?
- Jake ? - Eben !
Eben !
Who the hell are these people , Eben ?
What do they want ?
We 'll figure that out when we get you guys someplace safe .
There 's a generator at the Utilidor .
No , that 's way out on the edge of town . We need someplace close to hide .
Now .
Charlie Kelso 's attic .
It has a pull-down ladder . You can 't tell it 's there .
He would 've boarded up his home before he left .
Which is exactly why it 's a good idea .
We 'll pull down a board to get in , then we 'll tack it back .
Carter .
I want you to lead everybody as close to the buildings as possible .
If you hear anything , roll under a crawlspace .
Then , go straight to Kelso 's attic .
I 'll meet you there .
What are you gonna do ?
I 'm gonna load up with as many bear traps and flares as a 4x4 can carry .
Something 's gotta slow them down .
I 'm coming with you .
Okay .
- Fuck ! - Oh , shit !
Shit !
Fuck !
Eben !
No !
Go ! Get out of here !
Shit . Shit . Shit .
Move it . Move it !
Come on !
Go !
- What the hell is going on ? - I don 't know .
We gotta lose this thing .
And go where ?
We know a place .
Okay .
Go .
These seem to work .
It 's well hidden .
Hey .
Two , three .
I saw them ...
feed on Grandma Helen .
They 're like vampires , you know ?
Vampires don 't exist , Jake .
They don 't fall when you shoot them .
Hell , neither do I.
Well , I don 't care what they are . I just care what we do about them .
What are we gonna do about them ?
We 'll sleep in shifts .
We 'll ration our food , and then we 'll figure out the next step .
We have two advantages . We know this town ,
and we know the cold .
We live here for a reason .
Because nobody else can .
Yeah , right .
You did all that I asked .
We will take care of you .
The things they believe .
I guess it 's good you didn 't want kids , huh ?
Imagine .
Argh !
Where ... ? Where 's Catherine ? Where 's Catherine ?
- Dad . Dad . Dad . - What ?
Dad , Mom died a long time ago .
Isaac ...
you should go to sleep now .
You should go to sleep .
That 's right . That 's right . You should go to sleep .
Thank you .
They 're ransacking the Clarks ' place .
They 're tearing through everyone 's home .
We have to move .
When do you suggest we do that ?
Now ... while we have strength .
Until we have some way to stop them , it 's suicide , Lucy .
We can stay here until they find us , Eben ...
and they can kill us all , or we can run like hell !
Now , some of us won 't make it , but it 's better than all of us dying !
- Shut up ! - Doug , you should sit down .
Maybe Denise or Lucy dies , but that 's okay ...
so long you still have a chance ?
- Hey . Hey . - Hey .
Stupid !
Start a fight , that 'll get us all killed a lot faster .
Okay .
We go to the general store to get supplies , then we go to the Utilidor .
But we 'll never make it there without cover .
We get there ,
we can last the month .
The next blizzard , we 'll be ready .
Hello !
Somebody !
Help !
Come on .
Please !
Anyone ?
Hello ?
Help !
We need to get her in before they find her .
- Wait . - What ?
Look at the rooftops behind her .
Please !
They 're using her as bait .
Please .
Please , no . I tried .
There isn 't anybody left .
Please .
Please , God . Please .
God ?
No God .
Eben !
I 'll come to you .
I 've known Kirsten my whole life .
I 'm going out .
Why we waiting here for ever ? While they 're feeding on her ...
We could make a run for it and give it all we got !
- I can kill anything . I can kill these things . - We 'll die in here otherwise .
Eben doesn 't know what he 's doing !
- Just move . - Beau .
We agreed to keep the bigger weapon here .
- Just move ! - We need you here .
Okay .
Okay . Okay .
John .
How long have you been under there ?
I 'm not sure .
Where 's Ally ?
Took Ally .
Couldn 't follow .
You 're okay ?
My leg hurts .
Okay .
I know a safe place .
I 'm gonna pull you out .
But stay quiet .
Come on .
So hungry .
Yeah , we 'll get you something to eat . Yeah .
What happened to you ?
Shit !
Eben .
Come on .
John .
John ! Stay back ! Stay back !
Stay back !
John .
Are you hurt ?
- There 's blood . - He can 't breathe .
I 'm okay . I 'm okay .
Where 's your inhaler ?
I lost it .
Oh , shit .
I think ...
John Riis became one of them .
Translation and subtitles by PEPPER LALASPAIN * * * SONG LIVES FOR EVER * * *
Isaac !
No . Isaac !
- I 'm walking to Wainwright . - Shh !
It 's 80 miles . There 's no way to get there .
- Just go back upstairs . - Wilson !
Come on down . We need to get out of here . Bring your mother , too .
- Okay , we 'll die if you go out there . - No !
No . I 'll die if I stay here . That 's what 's gonna happen . Leave me alone .
What 's she doing ?
- Just ... Just keep quiet . - Leave me alone !
- I 'm sorry . - It 's all right .
Let 's just go back upstairs .
Can I ... ? There 's a bathroom ?
No ... Okay , remember you can 't flush .
We 'll just open the valve afterwards .
Who would have thought we 'd make it this long , huh ?
We 're ahead of the curve .
Every day they need more food . They 'll be back .
Dad ?
- Dad ! - ¡ Shh !
No noise !
- Wait ! You can 't just rush out . - He 's my father .
Wait ! No !
Stella , are you all right ? What happened ?
Isaac went to Wainwright .
- Wilson went to find him . - How long you been down here ?
Shh !
Dad !
¡ Arghhhhh !
I should 've fought harder .
Kept Wilson here .
It 's hard to stop someone when their family 's at stake .
The things you 'll do to save your own .
We were like that once .
Weren 't we ?
It 's gone .
It 's snowing .
As soon as it 's safe , we have to move .
You four , canned goods .
Stella , Carter , propane , batteries .
Jake , medical supplies . We meet back here in two minutes .
Let 's go !
I promised my wife I wouldn 't live on these things while she was gone .
She 'll cut you slack .
Shhh !
Oh , God !
I 'm done playing with this one .
You wanna play with me now ?
Come on !
What ?
Okay .
Wait .
Somebody !
Somebody get the ax !
She ...
She was just a girl .
You did the right thing .
It 's okay .
Who was she ?
I mean , does anybody recognize her ?
No .
The whiteout 's over .
We have to move .
We can 't stay here .
But the Utilidor 's too far without cover .
Eben ?
Could we make it to your station ...
if somebody created a diversion ?
How ?
These things can 't survive the sun .
What if we brought the sun early ?
Helen had that operation at home .
Yeah . She used an ultraviolet light to grow the stuff .
Yeah . I can run for her place , let them follow me .
Hit them with the sun lamp while the rest of you go to the sheriff 's station .
Just because something stopped Bela Lugosi ,
doesn 't mean it can stop these things .
Why would they send that stranger to cut us off ...
if the can handle the light ?
What if it doesn 't work ?
It has to .
I 'll do it .
- I 'm the fastest . - Bullshit .
I weigh less than you and I know Grandma 's house .
You 're 15 years old . Forget about it .
I 'm 15 . Right .
- You 've got a wife . People need you . - Jake .
I saw you in the back with the ax .
You think you 're up to doing that three or four more times ?
You don 't even think this plan will work .
Yeah , but you do .
I 'm going .
I 'll see you at the station .
You 'll need to start her genny first .
See you soon .
Hey !
- All right . - Go , go , go .
Come on , motherfuckers !
Hey !
Come on .
Come on !
Let me check .
Okay , quick . Come in .
Come on , Stella . You 're good .
You there ?
Yeah .
Yeah , it worked .
But they 're gonna cut off the power , so ...
Stella .
I got out .
It 's good to hear your voice .
Don 't wait for me .
Please .
Eben .
Run for Rogers Avenue ...
towards the trencher .
It 's my turn .
Do you understand ?
What can be broken must be broken .
Fuck off !
Welcome to Barrow .
Top of the world .
You ain 't gonna eat me .
When a man meets a force ...
he can 't destroy ...
he destroys himself instead .
What a plague you are .
Beau ...
And Doug .
Now there 's six of us .
Soon there 'll be just five .
The little girl in the store .
I changed .
I 'm just so thirsty now .
I couldn 't tell you .
That photo 's all I 've got left of my family .
Martha was taking the kids to visit her mom .
They were hit ...
by a drunk driver .
I wanted to be with them so much .
I ...
I couldn 't bring myself to doing it .
But I know they 're waiting for me .
I can 't live forever .
I can 't .
Eben ?
Don 't let me .
No , Carter .
He told us what he wants .
Did you see that ?
Yeah .
It 's Billy .
Billy .
It 's Peggy and the girls .
I heard the screams .
I didn 't want them to die like the rest .
I tried to shoot myself , too .
The fucking gun jammed .
I shouldn 't have signaled to you .
I just couldn 't stand being on my own .
You have a family !
You don 't ever hurt them !
Don 't ever hurt them .
Maybe they tried for the Utilidor .
Gail !
No . Stella .
Stella !
I 'll meet you at the Utilidor .
No , Billy , stay there ! Stay there ...
Eben !
Jake .
Stella ?
Gail Robbins ?
We don 't know .
It took centuries for us ...
to make them believe ...
we were only bad dreams .
We cannot give them a reason to suspect .
Destroy them all .
Go !
Stella , this is Eben .
Come in .
Where are you ?
Hello ?
Stella . This is Eben .
Come in .
Anyone ?
Eben !
Billy ! Bill . Hey ! Billy !
- Go ! - No ! Billy !
Shit ! Shit !
Eben !
Hey .
I found these behind Carter 's desk .
Chocolates , vitamins and vodka .
Stella , come in . This is Eben .
We should celebrate .
One day till sunrise .
You did good getting everybody here .
Eben .
Stella .
Whisper . They 're walking around .
I just had to hear your voice . I 've got Gail with me .
Where are you ?
Opposite the Melanson 's , under a wreck .
Are you okay ?
It 's so cold .
We 're freezing , Eben .
I can see the car . The wreck on the right .
We 're coming to get you .
There 's way too many of them .
They 'd kill us before we got to her .
We have to cut off or they 'll hear you .
I 'll call you back when it 's safe .
The sun comes up tomorrow .
We 're gonna watch it together .
I 'm so sorry , baby .
I should never have left you .
The street 's filling up with oil .
They broke into the pipeline .
They 're burning down the town .
Nobody will know what happened .
They 'll just think it was some horrible accident .
Next time they 'll take out Point Hope ... Wainwright .
Wait , wait .
This building 's strong . Can 't we just ride it out here ?
He 'll kill her if she runs .
She 'll burn if she stays .
You go out there , won 't they come after all of us ?
Oh , dear God .
Eben .
Eben !
Jake ...
when they 're all watching me ,
get on the walkie-talkie ...
and tell Stella to run for it .
What are you talking about ?
Eben !
When John Riis and Carter changed ,
they were only bitten .
They stayed who they were for a little while .
We can 't fight them the way that we are .
Thanks , little brother .
Take care of Stella for me .
- Are you fucking crazy ? - It 's somebody else 's blood .
He 's one of them .
How do we know he won 't attack us ?
- Maybe we should stop him now . - Shut up .
Shut up !
Nobody touches him .
I can smell your blood .
You can 't fight them all , Eben .
Stella , it 's Jake .
Get out of there now . Run !
The one who fights .
Come here .
Go !
What did you do to yourself ?
What I had to .
Should I go after them ?
It 's almost dawn .
- We made it . - Eben .
The dawn .
Translation and subtitles by PEPPER LALASPAIN * * * SONG LIVES FOR EVER * * *